자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회
(http://club.korea.com/friends)
Hey, guys / Hey
얘들아 안녕 / 안녕
Honey, I got us that room at the Woodford inn this weekend.
자기야, 이번 주말에
Woodford에 방 예약해놨어
Vermont(주)에?
That place in Vermont?
You can take a hint!
눈치가 있을때도 있구나!
잠깐만, 너네 이번 주말엔 어디가면 안되는데
에마의 생일이란말야
Wait, you can't go away this weekend.
It's Emma's birthday. / Yeah!
그래 / 파티할껀데
We're having a party.
Can't you just have the party when we get back?
파티는 우리가 온 다음에 하면 안되?
그건 말이 안되지
그럼 진짜 생일날이 아니잖아
No, that's silly. That won't be her real birthday.
Gee, if only she were one and had no idea
what the hell the birthday was.
에마가 한살이라서
생일이 뭔지도 모르면 얼마나 좋을까
제발 얘들아
우리한텐 정말 중요하다고
Come on, you guys. This is really important to us.
정말 미안한데, 챈들러랑 난
주말을 제대로 보내야 하거든
Oh, I'm sorry but Chandler and I
could really use a weekend away.
You know, to reconnect.....emotionally.
재결합을 위해서말야
감성적으로말이지
There's this thing I really want us to do.
I read about it in Maxim.
난 정말 하고 싶은게 있거든
격언책에서 읽었어
What? Can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
뭐라고?
Vermont에 다음날 가면 안돼?
그래, 모두 와줬으면 좋겠는데
Yeah, we want everyone to be there
As much as I hate to delay your doing
weird sex stuff to my little sister.
내 동생이랑 요상한 밤을 보내는걸
미루게 하고 싶지 않은만큼 원해
And I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
내 말은,이건 정말 중요하다고
I mean, how can we have her first birthday party
without her aunt and her uncle?
어떻게 고모랑 고모부도 없이
돌잔치를 할 수가 있겠어
Alright, we'll stay.
알았어
We can just drive up after the party.
파티 끝나고 가면 되지, 뭐..
Fine but if we end up not doing this Maxim thing
because of this party...
좋아, 하지만 이 파티 때문에
Maxim thing을 못하게 되면..
Believe me that is not why we won't be doing that.
무슨 일이 있어도
그건 안한다니깐!
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x04. The One With The Cake
Friends 10x04 TOW the Cake
Transcribed by Kevin Kim
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON NBC: 2003/10/23
영문대본/싱크
Kevin Kim(kkimlighte@korea.com)
한글번역
윤미내(minaii@korea.com)
테스트
이상민(albireon@hotmail.com)
게스트
강지연(strayship@korea.com)
자막편집/싱크수정
남효주(hyojunet@nate.com)
있잖아, 피비
나 어렸을 때, 생일이 되면
You know Pheebs.
When I was little, on my birthday,
my daddy would hide a present
in every room of the house,
아빠가 집의 모든 방에다
선물을 숨겨 놨었어
and then he would draw a treasure map
to help me find them all.
그리고는 그걸 다 찾으라고
보물지도를 그려주셨었어
Oh...I love family traditions like that.
오, 정말 멋진 전통이구나
When, uh, when Ursula and I were kids,
on our birthday,
언니랑 나랑 어렸을 적
생일 날엔...
our stepdad would sell his blood to buy us food.
우리 양아버지는 밥을 사주시려고
피를 파셨었대
Hey you guys / Hi
얘들아, 안녕 / 안녕
Hey I brought the camera for Emma's video.
에마 찍어주려고 카메라 가져왔어!
Oh, good, good! We have this idea to make a birthday video
for Emma and we'll give it to her when she's 18.
잘했어! 에마의 생일 비디오를 만들어서
에마가 18살 되면주려고
Oh, cool! Wow! It's like a time capsule. / Yeah
와 멋지다! 타임 캡슐 같은거네 / 맞아
생각해봐! 아직 개발되지도 않은 티비로
그 비디오를 보겠지?
Oh, just think! She's gonna be watching that video
on a TV that hasn't even been invented yet.
With friends who right now are just like babies
지금은 애기인 친구들하고 말야
그리고 개미인간들을 피하기 위해
And they'll be living in a floating city
that the humans built to escape the ant people.
사람들이 지어놓은
떠다니는 도시에 살고 있을테고
That's the hope!
희망사항이겠지
So is, uh, Emma awake yet?
근데 에마 아직 안깼어?
Oh no, it's still nap time but she'll be up soon.
아니, 아직 낮잠 시간이야
아마 곧 깰꺼야
Ah, where's Joey?
조이는 어디 갔어?
I said it's still nap time.
낮잠 시간이라고 했잖아
안녕, 조이 삼촌 / 안녕
Hey, there's uncle Joey. / Hey
Hey, say something to Emma
on her 18th birthday.
에마의 18살 생일을 위해
한마디 해줘
18, huh? / Joey, no!
18살? / 조이, 안되!
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
왜그래? 에마의
예쁜 친구들한테 하려는거야
When they see this, you'll be fifty two.
걔네들이 이걸 볼때면
넌 52살이야
And starting to think about settling down!
그리고 한사람한테
정착할 생각을 하고 있겠지!
Hey Joey, will you please set this up
for people to put Emma's presents on.
조이, 에마 선물 놓게
이것 좀 놔줄래?
그래 좋아
Love to. Yeah.
We were supposed to bring presents?
선물도 가져와야 되는 거였어?
그럼, 난 에마를 위해
노래를 준비했어
Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
아 그래?
그걸 내가 어떻게 알아?
조이, 생일 파티잖아
Joey, it's a birthday party.
Yeah but for a one year old. What's the point?
그렇긴 하지만, 겨우 한살이잖아
뭘 줘야 되는데?
The other day she laughed
for like an hour at a cup.
전에는 컵을 보더니
한시간을 웃더라구
Just, just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it
dressed as a farmer.
Elmo(주)가 농부 옷을 입은
그림이 있는 컵을 보고 말야
And he's standing next this cow.
그 옆엔 소 한마리가 그려있던데
The cow says "Elmoooo"
"Elmoooo"라는 소리를 내면서
Man..
세상에
That's a funny cup.
그 컵 정말 웃겨
Hey / Hey
안녕 / 안녕
Where's the birthday girl?
주인공은 어디 있나요
Oh, she's still napping.
아직 자고 있어
오, 그렇군. 아마 파티 생각에
밤새 한잠도 못잤을꺼야
Oh, sure. She was probably up all night
excited about the party she knows is happening.
이것봐. 너네들이 Vermont에
정말 가고싶은거 이해해
Look, I know that you guys really
want to get to Vermont
and this isn't a really big deal to you.
이게 너희들한텐 별일 아닌 것도 이해하고
But it really is to us. Okay?
하지만 우리한텐 정말 중요해, 알어?
Emma will never have her first birthday again.
에마한테 돌잔치는
평생 딱 한번뿐이잖아
Alright. You're right. We're sorry.
그래, 맞어
미안해
Now let's wake up Emma and
get the fun time started!
그러니까 이제 에마를 깨워서
신나게 놀아보자구!
No, really she didn't sleep well last night
so we can't wake her up.
안돼. 사실 에마가 어제 잠을 잘 못자서
아직 깨우면 안돼
Are you friggin' kidding me, Green?
지금 놀리는 겁니까, 그린양?!
안녕 / 안녕하세요
Hi / Hey
와주셔서서 감사해요
Glad you came.
I can't believe Emma's already one!
에마가 벌써 한살이라니
I remember your first birthday.
네 돌잔치 때엔 말이다
Ross was jealous of all the attention
we were giving you.
우리가 모두 너만 신경써주는걸
로스가 질투해가지고
He pulled on his testicles so hard
자기 그걸 너무 세게
잡아당기는 바람에
we had to take him to the emergency room.
응급실에 데려가야 했었단다
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
아빠에 대해
몰랐던 사실이지?
Hey, hey, Mr. and Mrs. Geller.
안녕하세요, 겔러 아저씨, 아줌마
Let me help you with that. / Thank you.
제가 받을께요 / 고맙다
Oh, man. This is great, huh?
세상에, 멋지지 않아요?
우리가 또 뭉치다니
Three of us together again?
You know what would be fun?
이러면 좋지 않을까요?
If we gave this present to Emma from all of us...
우리가 다같이 에마한테
이 선물을 주면 말이에요
넌 어느 쪽인데?
Which one are you?
I can't believe Emma's still asleep.
에마가 아직도 자고 있다니
I know! What are we going to do?
그러게말야! 어떻게하지?
좋은 생각이 있어
I've got a plan.
좋은 생각
I'm going to ram this platter
really hard onto your ribs.
이 접시로 네 갈비뼈를
세게 칠께
You're going to scream out
and that will wake her up.
네가 비명을 지르면
에마가 깰꺼야
나 이런 모니카랑은
Vermont에 가고 싶지 않은데
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
있잖아, 피비
Hey, Pheebs. You know what?
I was thinking since you wrote a song
maybe I could do somthing for Emma using my talents.
넌 노래를 준비했으니깐
난 내 재주를 이용해서 뭘하면 좋을까?
그러면 너
So you're gonna...
hit on her?
에마를 꼬시겠다는거야?
No, no, no. My talents as an actor.
아니, 아니.
배우로서의 재능을 이용해서말야
You know, I could, like, maybe...
그러니까, 어떤거냐 하면...
책을 감정을 풍부하게
섞어서 읽어준다거나
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
Or you could stick a fork in an apple!
사과를 포크로 찌르거나!
Hey, I think Emma might like it.
야, 난 에마가 그걸 정말
좋아할 것 같다고 생각한거라고
Oh, Emma might like what?
에마가 뭘 좋아할 것 같다고?
Um...my present.
음.. 내 선물
Oh, what did you get her?
뭘 준비했는데?
Actually we prepared performances.
사실 우리는 공연을 준비했어
Well, separate performances.
따로 공연하는거지만
But equally real.
하지만 둘다 진짜야
Oh, that sounds like fun!
와, 재밌겠다!
Well, you know what? Actually...
이러면 어떨까? 사실은
People are getting a little antsy
waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
사람들이 에마가 깨는걸 기다리려니까
좀 지루해하고 있거든
So would you mind performing them once now?
그래서 말인데 먼저 한번
보여주면 안될까?
그래 좋아 / 응?
Sure, yeah / Yeah?
그, 그래 / 좋아?
O....kay / Okay?
Everybody, let's get this party started, huh?
여러분, 파티를 시작할께요
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform
a little something for us.
조이와 피비가 우리를 위해
뭔가를 보여준대요
Oh, great!
와, 멋진데?
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed going up there?
앞에 나서는 것 긴장되지 않아?
준비 하나도 안했는데말야?
having nothing prepared?
Hey, I do it every week with 3 cameras
pointing at me and the whole crew waiting.
야, 매주 카메라 세 대 앞에서 스텝들이
모두 보고 있는데도 그러는데, 뭘
So Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
조이, 뭘 보여줄꺼야?
Uh...I will be doing a dramatic reading
of one of Emma's books.
에마의 책 중 하나를
멋지게 읽어줄게
어, 그래
Oh. Okay.
Which one?
어떤 거?
Oh, well, it's, uh ...
음..그게..
에마가 좋아하는 책 중에서
One of her favorites.
Riding the storm out:
coping with postpartum depression. Yeeesh!
산후 우울증 극복하는 법
앗, 이런!
Love you forever.
영원히 사랑할께요
'Love you forever by Robert Munch.' 작가 Robert Munch
Love you forever by Robert Munch.
published by Firefly books. Printed...
Firefly books 출판 인쇄는..
in Mexico.
멕시코
A mother held her new baby
엄마는 아기를 안고 있어요
and very slowly rocked him back and forth
앞뒤로 천천히 흔들어 주면서
앞으로 뒤로
Back and forth. Back and forth.
And while she held him, she sang
"I'll love you forever
그러면서 아기에게 노래를 불러줍니다
"영원히 사랑할께요"
I'll like you for always as long as I'm living
"내가 살아있는 한 영원히
좋아할께요"
my baby you'll be."
"내 아가여"
And while he rocked her, he sang
그러는동안 그는 노래를 불러요
"I'll love you forever. I'll like you for always.
"영원히 사랑할께요
항상 좋아할래요"
"내가 살아있는한
내 아가여"
As long as I'm living, my baby you'll be."
Wow!
와!
That was amazing.
정말 대단했어
선물 정말 고마워
Thank you so much for that gift.
I was not ready for this today.
오늘 이런 일
준비가 안됐는데
Amazing, amazing.
멋져, 멋졌어
Oh, Phoebe. I'm sorry.
오, 피비. 미안해
피비도 선물을 준비했대요
Phoebe has prepared something as well.
That's right. I prepared a song for Emma.
맞아. 난 에마를 위한
노래를 준비했어
From my heart to hers.
내 진심이야
For there's no greater gift
than the gift of music.
음악보다 좋은 선물은 없어
♪ 에마! ♪
♪ Emma! ♪
♪ 네 이름은 딜레마에요 ♪
♪ Your name poses a dilemma ♪
♪ Cause not much else rhymes with Emma ♪
♪ Emma엔 각운이 별로 없으니까요 ♪
♪ Maybe the actor Richard Crenna ♪
♪ 배우 Richard Crenna(주)가 있긴 해요 ♪
♪ He played the commanding officer in Rambo ♪
♪ 람보에 사령관으로 나왔죠 ♪
♪ Happy birthday , Emma ♪
♪ 생일 축하해요 에마 ♪
Is that it?
그게 끝이야?
No, of course not.
물론 아니지
그리고 나는 또
No, no, I've also, you know,
prepared a reading.
읽을 걸 준비했어
섹스와 미혼모
Sex and the single mother.
Finding your G-spot.
G-spot(주)찾기
No!
안돼!
안녕, 에마
18살 생일 축하한다
Hello Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
Right now that seems so far away.
Seventeen years.
지금은 아주 먼 얘기 같구나
17년이라니
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then and we'll be...
그래, 넌 커서 어른이
되어 있을테고, 우리는..
Well, your grandfather and I might not be here.
음, 너의 할아버지랑 나는
아마 살아있지 않을 수 있겠구나
맞아. 이 메세지는 무덤에서
너한테 가고 있는 거란다, 에마야
That's true. This message could be coming to you
from beyond the grave, Emma.
After all, my parents died very young.
우리 부모님들도
젊어서 돌아가셨거든
And my cholesterol's off the charts!
내 콜레스테롤 수치도 높고!
기억하렴, 에마야
Remember, Emma.
심장병으로 여자도 죽는단다
Heart disease kills women, too.
그만하세요!
Okay, cut!
좋아요. 아주.. 잘..
Great, great. That was, that was just...yeah.
Ross, um, don't forget to get
a shot of Emma's cake.
로스, 에마의 케잌
사진찍어두는거 잊지마
냉장고 안에 박스에 있어 / 알았어
It's in a box in the fridge. / Okay, sure.
Oh, you're gonna love this cake.
정말 마음에 들거야
New Jersey의 Carino's에서 사온건데
I got it from a bakery in New Jersey, Carino's .
Oh my God. That place has the creamiest frosting.
세상에, 거기 케잌 크림 정말 맛있는데!
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
어렸을 때, 거기까지
히치하이크해 가기도 했어
음, 어쨌거나, 거기엔 여러가지 모양의
새로운 케잌이 아주 많거든
Well, anyway. They make these great novelty cakes
in all different shapes and if you give them a photo
사진을 맡기면
they'll copy it in icinig.
모양을 새겨주기도 해
Oh, did you do a picture of Emma?
에마 사진으로 했어?
Yes, on a cake shaped like a bunny.
응, 토끼 모양 케잌에다가
어? 레이첼, 그 빵집 혹시
Oh, Rach. Does this bakery by any chance also bake
야한 모양 케잌도 만들어?
erotic cakes?
Say, for bachelorette parties?
처녀파티용 같은거?
로스, 무슨 소리 하는..
Ross, what are you talking...
Oh, My God!
어머 세상에!
They put my baby's face on a penis!
우리 아기 얼굴을
남자 거기에다 넣었어!
Oh, now it's a party!
와, 이제 파티 시작이네!
You guys, this isn't funny. Alright?
이건 하나도 안웃겨, 알았어?
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster,
I would've baked it myself!
케잌을 망치려고 했다면
그냥 내가 만들 했겠지!
Uh....Is it okay that I still think it looks delicious?
저기..
그래도 맛있어 보이는데
내가 이상한거야?
잭, 이거 봐요
Jack, look at this.
I know what you're thinking, Judy.
당신이 무슨 생각 하는지 알아
무섭게 닮았다니깐!
The resemblance is uncanny.
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
나 또 거기를 잡아당길 지경이야
No, no, this is not what I ordered.
아니에요. 내가 주문한게 아니라구요
Okay? I went all the way to New Jersey
우리 딸 생일을 위해
so that I could have the perfect cake
for my daughter's birthday
완벽한 케잌을 사러
뉴저지까지 간거라고요
and I need a bunny cake right now!
토끼 모양 케잌이
당장 필요하다고요!
Ask him if it will be faster
if we cut the baby's face off the penis
거시기서 우리 아가 얼굴을 잘라주면
더 빨리 해줄 수 있나 물어 봐
그래서 토끼한테 붙이면 되는지
so we could put it on the bunny.
That is a weird sentence.
말이 좀 그렇네
Oh, believe you me,
그렇다니깐요
I am going to bring this cake back.
이 케잌 들고 갈거에요
I don't even want it in my home.
집에 놔두기도 싫다고요
조이, 만지지마!
Joey, don't touch it!
I'm so confused!
난 당황스럽다니깐!
네, 우리 아기 사진을
토끼 케잌에 붙여 주세요
Yes, yes, I still want my daughter's picture
but on a bunny cake
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
노란 케잌이요
땅콩 엊은 초콜렛 크림!
To be fair, this one does have nuts.
그래도 여기 땅콩은 있네
모니카, 레이첼이 케잌 가지러 가게
차 빌려줘서 고마워
Hey, Mon. It was really nice of you
to loan Rachel your car so she could go get the cake.
It was so nice of her to pull my hair till I dropped the key.
내가 열쇠를 떨어뜨릴 때까지
내 머리 잡아 당겨줘서 내가 고맙지
Well, you know, while we're waiting, you guys could
tape your message to Emma for her 18th birthday, huh?
있잖아, 기다리는 동안에
에마의 18살 생일을 위해 메세지 남겨줄래?
시작해
Okay.
안녕, 에마
지금은 2020년이야
Hi Emma. It's the year 2020.
Are you still enjoying your nap?
아직도 낮잠 자고있니?
우리는 모니카 고모랑
챈들러 고모부란다
We're aunt Monica and uncle Chandler by the way.
우리를 못알아 볼지도 모르겠구나
너희 부모님이랑 말 안한지가
You may not recognize us
because we haven't spoken to your parents
since 17 years!
17년이나 됐거든!
우린 결혼한 사이였었는데
주말에 같이 여행을 못가는 바람에
We used to be married but then
we missed a weekend away together
and things kind of unraveled
잘 안풀렸지
because of you.
너 때문에
생일 축하한다
Happy birthday.
로스, 레이첼은 지금쯤은
끝날거라고 약속했었어
Ross, Rachel promised it would be over by now.
We seriously have to go if we want to get to Vermont.
Vermont에 가려면
지금 정말 가야해
I called them. The last train leaves in a half hour.
내가 전화해봤어
마지막 기차가 30분 후에 있대
And you know, I have a massage client soon.
난 마사지 약속이 있어
얘들아, 제발
조금만 더 기다려줘
You guys, just please. A little bit longer
I promise Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
레이첼이 케잌 가지고
금방 올거야
Monica, rememeber the frosting ? Huh?
모니카, 케잌 크림 기억나지?
좋아, 5분만이야
Alright, five more minutes.
여보세요
Hello.
Oh no, what happened?
세상에, 무슨 일이야?
What? Okay. Okay. Where are you?
뭐라고? 알았어. 어디야?
Okay, I'll be right there.
알았어. 지금 갈께
Was that Emma? Is she up?
에마야? 일어났대?
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
레이첼이 속도 위반으로 걸렸대
She forgot her license
so now I have to bring it to her.
면허증을 안가지고 가서
내가 가서 데리고 와야 할거 같아
Well, if you're leaving I'm definitely gonna go.
너가 가면 나도 갈래
Wait! If anybody gets to go, it's us.
잠깐만! 누군가가 간다면
그건 우리야!
우리가 제일 오랫동안 불평했다고
We've been complaining the longest.
안돼. 떠나면 안된다고
Wait, you guys. No, no. You can't leave.
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
레이첼은 벌써 케익 때문에
기분이 안좋단말야
How do you think she's gonna feel
when she comes back here
레이첼이 방에 돌아왔을때
너희들이 다 가버렸으면
and all of you guys are gone?
기분이 어떨거 같아?
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
몰라. 월요일에 얘기해주면 되겠네
조이, 너한테 맡길게
Joey, you're in charge, okay?
You make sure nobody leave.
아무도 못가게 해
Got it!
알았어!
Hey, hey, hey. Where do you think you're going?
야, 야, 야, 어딜 가는거야?
To the bathroom.
화장실
좋아, 나머지 사람들은
편하게 있어도 좋아
Alright, well, the rest of you get comfortable, okay?
Because we're gonna be here for a .....
어차피 여기 꽤 오래....
Wait a minute. There's a window in there.
잠깐. 저긴 창문이 있잖아
Oh, no! He's not getting away that easy.
안돼! 그렇게 쉽게
빠져나가게 둘 순 없어
뭐하는 짓이야? 당장 나가!
What are you doing? Get the hell out of here!
That one did not have Emma's face on it.
저긴 에마 얼굴이 안붙어있네
Um, no, it did not.
응, 없었어
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
우린 이만 가봐야겠다
너무 늦었어
Jack's not allowed to drive at night anymore.
이 사람은 이제 밤에 운전하면 안되거든
차선도 못 따라가
He has trouble staying in his lane.
Last winter I went up on a church lawn
and drove right through a manger scene.
지난 겨울에 교회 잔디밭에 들어가서
말구유통 장면에 들이 받았지.
신문에서는 증오범죄(주)라고 생각하나보더라.
The papers thought that it was a hate crime.
어쨌든 보게돼서 즐거웠다
Anyway, it was lovely seeing you.
Okay / Bye.
네 / 잘있거라
잘있어라, 얘들아
Bye dear.
안녕히 주무세요 / 잘자라
Nighty night / Nighty night
Joey, how could you just let them leave?
조이, 저 분들은 왜 보내드리는거야?
헤이, 헤이
로스 아버지한테는 함부로 못한다고
Hey, hey, hey. I'm not gonna mess with Jack.
He's a great man. He fought for our country.
대단한 사람이잖아
우리나라를 위해 싸웠다고
No, he didn't.
그런적 없어
He pretended to be a quaker to get out of Korea.
한국에서 나오려고 퀘이커교도(주)인척 했단말야
허! 그럼 이젠 아무도 못 나가
Huh! Well, that's it. He's the last one to go.
너희들을 가둘거야
I'm locking you guys in.
그거 내가 반대로 돌려서
나갈 수 있는건 알지?
You do know I can just turn them
the other way around. Right?
네가 여기 살았다는걸 깜빡했다
Oh, forgot you used to live here.
여보세요
Hello.
Joey, it's Estelle.
조이, 나 에스텔이야
Hey.
안녕하세요
So how did your audition go today?
오늘 오디션은 어땠어?
What audition?
무슨 오디션요?
The one I told you about last week.
지난주에 말한거 말이야
네? 오디션에 대해서 한마디도 안했어요
What? You never said anything about an audition.
Let me start over.
자, 시작 해보자
I just got a call about an audition.
방금 오디션에 관한 전화 한통을 받았는데
I think you can still make it.
아마 아직 시간이 될거야
It's down at the Aster theater
애스터 극장이고
and you need to have a monologue prepared.
독백을 준비해서 가야해
A monologue? I don't have a ....
독백이요? 전 준비가...
I got it.
됐어요
어, 그럼 난 가봐야겠어
Uh, so, I'm gonna take off.
뭐?
What?
안돼! 절대 못 가
No way! You don't get to leave.
곧 내 방에 마사지 고객이 도착할거야
I've got a massage client
waiting outside my door any minute.
그래, 그리고 우린 우리가 벌써
들어가 있어야 하는 방값을 지불했다구
Yeah, and we paid for a room
that we're supposed to be in right now.
Well, okay, now.
좋아
Only one of us has to stay with Emma.
우리중에 한사람만 에마랑 같이 남으면 돼
Okay and as the person who realized that I get to go.
난 그걸 깨달은 사람이니까 가야겠어
안돼 안돼 안돼
No, no,no, no, no.
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
누가 남을지 공평하게
정할 방법을 생각해보자
Oh! I got it.
좋아! 생각났어
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to ten, alright?
자, 다들 1부터 10까지
숫자 중에 하나씩 고르는거야
누구든 제일 높은 숫자를
고르는 사람이 먼저 나가는거야
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
Okay, ten.
좋아, 10
Okay. Monica picks ten and I call nine. Anyone else?
좋아, 모니카는 10을 불렀고
난 9야. 다른 사람은?
안돼, 그냥...
그냥 제비뽑기로 하자
No, let's just, let's just draw straws.
Or we could flip a coin and then multiply the...
아니면 동전을 던져서 곱하는데...
I'm beggin you to stop. / Alright.
제발좀 그만해 / 알았어
Ok, how about this?
좋아, 이건 어때?
We got wind-up toys for Emma for her birthday.
에마 생일선물로 사온 태엽장난감들 있지?
We can make them race and
그걸 가지고 경주를 하는거야
whoever comes in last stays.
제일 늦게 들어오는 사람이 남기
Yeah, let's do that!
예, 그거 좋다
우리가 버몬트에서 하려고
생각한거보다 더 재밌겠는데!
That sounds more fun
than the thing we're gonna do in Vermont!
다들 장난감을 골라! / 그래
Everybody, pick the toys! / Okay.
난 돌고래!
I want the dolphin!
That's a bear.
- 그거 곰이야
- 나 너무 흥분했어!
I'm too excited!
그래, 피비 넌 곰으로 하고
Okay, Phoebe, you get the bear.
Joey, you get the robot.
조이, 넌 로봇을 하고
And Chandler and I get the dog. Okay?
챈들러랑 나는 개로 할래, 오케이?
And the race is going to go from here to here.
그리고 경주는...
여기부터... 여기까지
Now the one who comes in last.... stays!
제일 늦게 들어오는 사람이...
남는거야!
Okay, ladies and gentlemen, wind your toys.
신사숙녀 여러분
태엽을 감아주세요!
줄서고, 준비... 땅!
On your mark, get set.... go!
빨리빨리! / 빨리가 로봇!
Go, go! / Come on, Robot!
뭘보고 짖는거야?
What are you barking at?
How is that going to help?
그게 도움이 돼?
내가 산건데 왜 저놈이
그거 밖에 할줄 모른다는걸 까먹은거지?
I bought you! How did I forget
that that's all you do?
잘했어, 로봇!
Way to go, robot!
Good job, Alan!
잘했어, 알란!
좋은 경주였어 / 그래
Hey, good race, you guys / Yes.
나중에 봐
See you later.
No, no, no, wait.
안돼, 안돼, 기다려
We didn't lose.
우린 아직 안졌어
The rules clearly stated that the last one
to cross the finish line was the loser.
룰은 마지막으로 결승선을
지나는 사람이 지는거야.
Well, our dog never crossed the finish line
so technically....
그리고, 우리 개는 절대 결승선을
지난 적이 없으니까 엄밀히 따지면...
They left.
애들 갔어
No, there's no time to go to bakery.
빵집까지 갈 시간이 없어.
그냥 집으로 갈거야
We're just gonna come home.
다 떠났다고?
Everybody left?
Alright, well, just tell Emma
that we'll be there as soon as we can.
알았어, 그냥 에마한테
우리가 최대한 빨리 갈거라고 말해줘
안녕
Bye.
레이첼! / 오 안돼, 미안
Rachel! / No! God, sorry.
I can't believe they gave you a ticket.
You're such a good driver.
이렇게 운전을 잘하는데
왜 딱지를 끊었나 몰라
에마가 깼대
Emma's awake.
그래?
Yeah?
I can't believe this.
믿을 수가 없어
This is her first birthday. She's awake.
We're not even there.
에마 첫 생일인데
에마가 일어났는데 우리가 없다니
다들 떠났대. 우리는 저 멍청하고
추접스런 케익을 아직도 가지고 있고
Everybody left.
We still have the stupid obscene cake.
어쩌면 내가 좀 손볼 수 있을지도 몰라
Well, maybe I can fix that.
You know? Try to, try to turn it into something else.
뭐.. 다른 모양으로 바꿀 수 있을지도 모르고
더 망치지마
Oh, don't even bother.
벌써 에마 첫 생일도 망쳤다고
I've already ruined her first birthday.
이런 어릴적 경험들이
얼마나 중요한지 알아, 로스?
Do you know how important
these early experiences are, Ross?
Very.
굉장히
According to the back cover of
that book you gave me.
네가 준 책 뒷표지에 써있더라
레이첼, 에마는 기억도 못할거야
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
I guess.
그렇겠지
오늘이 얼마나 멋질지 얼마나 생각을 했는데
Oh, I just had such an idea
what this day would be like. You know?
에마는 웃고 모두들 케익 주위에
모여서 생일축하 노래를 부르고
Emma laughing and everybody gathered around her cake
singing happy birthday.
Then we would all go into the...
그러구 나서 다들 같이...
헤이, 당장 비켜
초보운전 주제에!
Hey, get off the road, you stupid student driver!
They have to learn!
저 사람들도 배워야지
Hey, this isn't that bad.
이거 괜찮은데?
Oh my God!
세상에
Look, you made it into a bunny!
How did you do that?
그걸 토끼로 바꿨네? 어떻게 한거야?
Well, I just made these two things, um,cheeks .
음, 이 두개를 볼로 만들었고
And then I split this to make ears.
이걸 나눠서 귀로 만들었지
Wel,, I'm very impressed.
정말 대단하다
누군 노래하고. 누군 춤추고
Some can sing. Some can dance.
I apparently can turn phallic cakes
into woodland creatures
난 거시기를 토끼로 바꿀 수 있지
Another way to organize your stuffed animals
is by size.
니 동물들을 정리하는
다른 방법은 크기별로 정리하는거야
I'm sorry. Is this a game for Emma or for Monica?
미안한데. 이거 에마용 게임이야?
모니카용 게임이야?
게임?
Game?
에마, 오늘이 네 생일인걸 알기는 하니?
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today?
너 한살이야
You're one.
One year old.
한살박이라구
That's little.
진짜 쪼그만거야
Huh! That's my girl!
허! 얘 좀 봐!
That's how old you are.
그게 네 나이야
Did I teach her that?
내가 가르친거야?
내가 지혜를 전한거야?
Did I just impart wisdom?
I want one.
나도 애기 하나 있었으면 좋겠다
Me too.
나도야
아무도 없는데 그냥 얠 데려갈까?
There's no one around.
Why don't we just take this one?
And head to Canada.
그리고 캐나다로 가는거야
I was kidding.
난 농담한거야
난 아냐. 가자!
I wasn't! Let's get going!
Hey.
얘들아
Are Ross and Rachel back?
로스랑 레이첼 돌아왔어?
No, not yet.
아니, 아직
Oh good! I didn't miss the party.
잘됐다. 아직 파티 안끝났구나
마사지 손님은 어쩌구 온거야?
What about your massage client?
그렇게 가버린게 너무 미안해서
I just felt so bad missing this
so I just slipped him a little something.
손님한테 뭘 좀 먹였지
You know, as long as I'm back in 5 or 6 hours,
it will be alright.
5~6 시간내에 가기만 하면 괜찮을거야
휴, 로스랑 레이첼이 물어보면
난 계속 여기 있었던거야
Okay, if Ross and Rachel ask,
I've been here the whole time.
The whole time!
계~속!
I've been here the whole time.
난 계속 여기 있었어
Joey, we just saw you come in.
조이, 니가 들어오는거 봤어
You ran past us on the stairs.
계단에서 우릴 앞질러 올라갔잖아
뭐 떠났었어도 상관없어
I don't care that you left.
I'm just glad that you're here.
지금 여기 있어서 너무 기뻐
Thanks you guys.
고마워, 얘들아
Hey guys, come on.
얘들아, 이리 와봐
You've got to see what Emma just did.
에마가 방금 뭘 했는지 봐야돼
What?
뭔데?
Emma, how old are you?
에마, 네가 몇살이지?
How old are you today?
오늘 네가 몇살이지?
Oh, Emma, that's right! You're that many!
오, 에마, 그래
그게 네 나이야!
세상에! 우리 딸은 천재야!
Oh my God! Our daughter's a genius!
- 레이첼, 그럼 얘를...
- 안돼, 과학캠프는 안보내
Rach, this means.../ No, no science camp
Damn it!
젠장!
I'll put a candle on a cake.
케익에 촛불 붙일께
오, 에마. 네 인형들이
깔끔하게 줄서있는것좀 봐
Oh, Emma. Look at your stuffed animals
lined up so neatly.
고마워
Thanks.
Okay, here we go!
자, 여기있습니다!
에마의 첫 생일케익입니다
Emma's first birthday cake.
Hey Emma, you want to blow out the cake?
에마, 촛불 불어서 꺼야지?
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
자, 에마야. 할 수 있어
What's wrong? Are you okay?
왜그래? 괜찮아?
Oh, yeah, nothing.
어, 아냐
It's happy tears.
그냥 기뻐서
This is just what I wanted.
이게 바로 내가 원했던거야
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
어, 이거 토끼로 만들었네
난 뭐가 문제지?
What is wrong with me?!
It looked more delicious when it was a penis!
거시기일 때가 훨씬 맛있어 보였단말야!
Okay / Okay, you ready?
좋아 / 좋아, 준비됐어? / 응
Yeah.
음.. 녹화 / 좋아
And... record / okay
Hi Emma.
안녕, 에마
Well, your first birthday is over.
니 첫번째 생일이 지나갔단다
좀 이...
And it was weird....
고!고!고! 알란
Go, go , go , Alan
아냐 이 털만 많은 바보야!
Wrong! You hairy bastard!
자막에 대한 피드백은
동호회 게시판으로 해주십시요
You can freely distribute this without my permission
But don't take the credit for yourself.